<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Sikh Gyan</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="katha1Title">Guru Nanak Dev Ji Grazing Buffaloes</string>
    <string name="Katha11">Guru Nanak Dev Ji’s father once sent Guru Nanak Dev Ji to graze buffaloes in the pastures. While grazing buffaloes, Guru Nanak Dev ji sat under a tree and started meditating on God. Meanwhile, the herd of buffaloes went into the neighboring farmer’s field and destroyed his crop. The farmer saw his crops getting damaged. He became furious and lodged a complaint with Rai Bular, the officer-in-charge of that area. Rai Bular came to inspect the fields, and to his astonishment, he found no damage was done to the crops; rather, the crops were blossoming. The place, at which this miracle took place, is known as Kiara Sahib.</string>
    <string name="Katha12">On another occasion, Guru Nanak Dev Ji was sent to graze the buffaloes in the pastures and he fell asleep under the shade of a tree. As the sun rose higher, the shadow moved away. The rays of the hot summer sun began to fall on Guru Nanak Dev Ji’s face. A big cobra came at that place and provided shadow with its hood over the face of the Divine Master. Rai Bular was going through that area with his attendants. When he saw this strange scene, he was convinced that Guru Nanak Dev Ji is not an ordinary person. God had sent him to this world. Rai Bular then touched the Gurus  feet in great reverence and thus became his disciple.</string>
    <string name="katha2Title">Bhai Lalo and Malik Bhago</string>
    <string name="Katha21">Guru Nanak Dev Ji traveled to a number of places, including Saidpur, now known as Eminabad. Before Guru Ji arrived at Saidpur, the word has spread in the whole city that a holy man is going to visit their town. Malik Bhago was the chief of the town. He was a corrupt person and who had earned a lot of wealth through unfair means. He would charge extra tax to the poor farmers and would take most of their crop, leaving them hungry. He had become a wealthy person by taking other’s belongings. When Malik heard the news of Guru Ji’s arrival, he started preparing for Guru’s stay at his house.</string>
    <string name="Katha22">When Guru Nanak reached Saidpur, he knocked on the door of a poor carpenter named Lalo. Guru Ji chose to stay with Lalo for sometime as a guest. Lalo would serve Guru Ji with little food he could afford and Guru Ji would eat the simple food with love. News reached Malik Bhago that Guru Ji was staying with Lalo. Malik held a big gathering and invited all the holy men including Guru Nanak Dev Ji. Guru Ji did not accept his invitation. </string>
    <string name="Katha23">Malik became very angry that Guru Nanak Dev Ji refused his proposal and ordered to force the Guru to visit his place. Two guards were sent to Lalo’s home to escort Guru Ji. Guru Nanak Ji decided to go visit Malik’s palace. When Guru Ji reached Malik’s palace, Malik Bhago said, “O holy man, I have prepared so many dishes for you, but you are staying with a poor carpenter and eating his dry bread? Why?” </string>
    <string name="Katha24">The Guru replied, "I cannot eat your food because your bread is ill-begotten and has been made with money sucked from the poor through unfair means, while Lalo's bread is made from the hard-earned money.” Malik Bhago very mad after heariong Guru Ji’s remarks and asked Guru Ji to prove his point. Guru Nanak Dev Ji asked for a loaf of bread from Lalo's house. In one hand the Guru held Lalo's dry bread and in the other he held Malik Bhago's bread. Guru Ji then squeezed both breads with his hands. Milk dripped out from Lalo's bread while blood dripped from Malik Bhago's bread. Malik Bhago was completely shaken by his guilt and asked for forgiveness. Guru Ji asked him to distribute his ill-gotten wealth among the poor and henceforth live an honest life. Malik Bhago was re-born with the Guru's blessing. He started living an honest life.</string>
    <string name="katha3Title">Sajjan Rogue</string>
    <string name="Katha31">During one of his journeys, Guru Nanak Dev Ji met a Rogue named Sajjan. Sajjan always wore a white dress, displayed his rosary beads and thus posed to be a holyman. He had built a Hindu temple and a Muslim mosque at the courtyard of his residence. He would invite travellers to his residence to rest for the night. During the night, he would take away their goods and money and would kill the travellers. He had a well near his house where he would dump the bodies of the guest he killed. </string>
    <string name="Katha32">Guru Nanak Dev Ji arrived at his place and stayed with him for the night. At night, the Guru did not go to bed, which made Sajjan nervous to perform his nefarious act of robbing. Sajjan asked the Guru to take rest and sleep but Guru ji replied, "God's minstrel do not go to sleep till God sends word that he should rest." The Guru then asked Mardana to play the rebec and he sang, “Houses, mansions, palaces painted on all sides are left hollow when thy breath stops. You posses wealth and assets; nothing shall go along with you in the end except the sins you commit. You call yourself clever and smart, but you are unaware that you can perish in a moment. You have not remembered God. You are completely drenched in money. You have not loved the one who gave you the body and breath. When the death comes, you shall tremble helplessly. Have you sung the praises of Lord; He would have been your support at the time of your death.” </string>
    <string name="Katha33">When Sajjan listened the Divine melody, he realized that Guru Ji’s words were actually addressed to him. Upon hearly the sermin, he made his obeisance and fell at Guru Ji’s feet, and prayed to him to pardon his sins. Guru Ji said, "Sajjan, in the Sovereignty of God, grace is obtained by two things, open confession and reparation for wrong." Sajjan stood in submission. Guru Nanak Dev Ji asked him to give all of his ill-gotten wealth to the poor. He obeyed the mandate, became a follower of the Guru and started meditating on God regularly.</string>
    <string name="katha4Title">Kauda the Cannibal</string>
    <string name="Katha41">During one of his mission to enlighten people, Guru Nanak Dev Ji traveled a great distance to the wilderness of Assam with his companions, Bala and Mardana. Mardana was very hungry and tired, so they sat under a tree. After sometime, Mardana went to get something to eat. On his way he met Kauda, the cannibal. Kauda took Mardana by surprise and bounded his hand and foot by a rope and then carried him to the spot where he had kept a big pan full of oil for frying the flesh of his victims. Kauda started to lighten fire under the pan. When Mardana saw Kauda preparing to butcher him, he was very frightened and prayed to Guru Ji to come to his rescue. The all-knowing Guru realized what was happening to Mardana. He started walking towards Kauda’s place in order to rescue Mardana.</string>
    <string name="Katha42">Kauda was trying to light the fire when Guru ji appeared. Kauda was completely bewildered. He went towards the Guru and tied him as well. He lit the fire and within minutes the oil was burning hot. Guru Nanak Dev Ji said that he wants be the first one to be fried. Kauda was astonished and surprise. He had never seen anyone like Guru Nanak before. Kauda carried on his routine and lifted Guru Ji to be put him in the big pan. </string>
    <string name="Katha43">When the Guru’s feet touched the hot oil, it became cold as ice. Kauda then knew that Guru Nanak Dev Ji was not an ordinary person. Guru Ji looked at Kauda with compassion and graciously and said, "Kauda! You do not realize what you are doing. Would you cast yourself in the burning fire of hell?" Kauda, whose conscience was dead with heinous crimes, suddenly came to realization and was overwhelmed with repentance. The very gracious and holy sight of the divine Guru made him realize his guilt and he fell at Guru’s feet and begged for mercy. The gracious Guru blessed him with Naam, the meditation on the Name of God. Kauda changed entirely and thereafter lived as a devout disciple of Guru Nanak Dev Ji. He became an honest person and a devotee of God.</string>
    <string name="katha5Title">Wali Qandhari, the Arrogant Priest</string>
    <string name="Katha51">After traveling through Middle East and many other countries, the Guru reached a place called Hassan Abdal. It is about fifty kilometers from Rawalpindi in Pakistan. Guru Ji stayed at Hassan Abdal near the foothills. People came to know about Guru Ji and began to gather around him. Guru Ji talked to them about God. He told them the greatness of God and His creation. Numerous people began to gather around him every day.</string>
    <string name="Katha52">A Muslim Priest lived on the top of a hill. His name was Bawa Wali Qandhari. His house was near a spring of fresh water. The water flowed down to the town from spring on top of the hill near Wali\'s house. The spring was the only source of water for the town. People relied on the spring to carry their basic needs.</string>
    <string name="Katha53">Wali Qandhari was an arrogant person. When he saw people gathering around Guru Nanak instead of his place, he became very jealous and angry. He stopped the spring water from flowing down to the town. The people became frustrated. How could they and their cattle live without water? A group of them went to Bawa Wali Qandhari and begged him to let the water flow down as before. Bawa Wali Qandhari in full anger said, "Go to your Guru, the one you visit everyday and ask for water from him." The poeple went to the Guru and told him the whole story. Guru Ji said, “Don\'t lose your heart, trust in God. God will not let you die of thirst”. Guru Ji then asked Bhai Mardana to go and appeal to Bawa Wali Qandhari and request him to let the water flow down to the town. When Bhai Mardana went to the top of the hill, Bawa Wali Qandhari shouted angrily, “Go back to your Guru and ask him to give water to the people.”</string>
    <string name="Katha54">Bhai Mardana returned to the Guru and narrated what Bawa Wali Qandhari said to him. The Guru sent him once again but Mardana came back with the same story. People got more and more frustrated each second. The Guru said, “Don\'t lose your heart. God is great and merciful. God can make springs flow from where ever He wishes. Let us all pray to Him.” They all prayed. Then Guru Nanak Dev Ji lifted a stone. At once, a stream of fresh water began to flow from the place Guru lifted the stone.</string>
    <string name="Katha55">At the same time, Bawa Wali Qanhari\'s spring dried up. He was filled with anger and pushed a large rock from the top of the hill towards the Guru. The rock came rolling down towards the Guru. Bawa Wali Qanhari thought that the rock would crush Guru Ji to death but the Guru quietly raised his hand and the rock stopped at the instant it struck Guru\’s hand. Guru ji\’s hand was imprinted on the rock. Bawa Wali Qundhari\'s pride was broken. He came down and fell at the Guru\'s feet. The Guru said, “Rise my friend. Live as devotees of God should live. Be kind and share with everyone” The rock still exists. There is a beautiful Gurdwara at that place called the Panja Sahib.</string>
    <string name="katha6Title">Realization of Offering Water to Ancestors at Haridwar</string>
    <string name="Katha61">Haridwar is one of the Hindu pilgrimages situated on the bank of river Ganges. As the sun comes out in the morning, people start throwing water with their hands towards the sun from the river. When Guru Nanak Dev Ji visited Haridwar, he asked the people as to what they were doing. A priest replied, “We are offering water to our dead ancestors in the region of Sun to quench their thirst.” </string>
    <string name="Katha62">Upon this, the Guru started throwing water towards the west. The Hindu pilgrims were astonished and asked Guru Nanak about what he was doing. The Guru replied, “I am watering my fields in Punjab.” The priest asked, “How can your water reach such a distance?” The Guru retorted, “How far your ancestors are from here?” One of them replied, “In the other world.”</string>
    <string name="Katha63">Guru Nanak Dev Ji stated, “If this water cannot reach my fields which are about four hundred miles away from here, how can your water reach your ancestors who are not even on this earth?” The crowd stood in dumb realization. Some of the listeners came to understand the point made by Guru Nanak Dev Ji. They realized that the water that they were throwing simply returned to the river and it is a fake belief that it could reach their ancestors.</string>
    <string name="Katha64">Guru Nanak Dev Ji preached against superstitions, false rituals, worship of demi-gods and goddesses. He stressed that only One God, the Formless, is to be glorified. In this way, he showed the path of truth and enlightenment. There is a Gurdwara called Nanakwara in Haridwar on the bank of the river Ganges where Guru Nanak Dev Ji stayed on his visit to Haridwar.</string>
    <string name="katha7Title">Why does God Himself helps His Devotees?</string>
    <string name="Katha71">Once a king in India went to Guru Nanak Dev Ji and asked, “O Guru! As you told us that God Himself supports His true worshiper, but God has so many apostles, why does He support His devotees Himself? Why does not He send His apostles to help the devotees?” As he said this, his own son who was playing at the bank of a nearby river slipped in the river. The king did not waited for a second and jumped in the river right after his son to save his child.</string>
    <string name="Katha72">After saving his child he returned to the Guru. The Guru asked, “My dear friend, you were sitting here with me a minute ago and why did you jump in the river?” King explained that his son had slipped in the river and he went to save him. Then the Guru asked, “Dear friend, you have so many servants then why did you jumped in the river by yourself? Why did not you send you servants to save him?” The King said, “When it come to my son. I do not want to take any chances and would do anything it takes to protect him. I love my son very much and I do not want to lose him at any cost.” </string>
    <string name="Katha73">Then Guru Ji said, “My dear friend, God loves His devotees the same way as you love your son. That is why he Himself saves His true worshipper.”</string>
    <string name="katha8Title">Tapa, the Monk</string>
    <string name="Katha81">A monk known as Tapa lived in Khadur. He was worshipped by some of the local villagers. Tapa was jealous of Guru Angad Dev Ji, the second Guru of Sikhs. He was jealous by the reverence shown to Guru by the people. He wanted to be considered as great as the Guru, so he looked forward for an opportunity to disgrace the Guru and earn some recognition for himself. One year, the village was hit by a drought and rain was nowhere in sight. Tapa started telling people that the drought was because of Guru Angad Dev Ji\'s presence in the town. He said, “If you expel the Guru, I will bring rain within twenty-four hours." Some people then started asking Guru Angad to leave the town. Ultimately, Guru Ji left the town and went seven villages away from Khadur where Tapa had no influence.</string>
    <string name="Katha82">When Baba Amar Das Ji arrived at Khadur the following morning, he could not find Guru Angad Dev Ji anywhere. On inquiry, the people narrated the whole story to Baba Amar Das. In the meantime Tapa failed to bring any rain. Baba Amar Das Ji told people about how great of a tyranny they have committed. They expelled the true Guru and followed a fake monk. The people began to realize their blunder. They went to Guru Angad Dev Ji, apologized and asked him to come back to the town. Guru Ji agreed to return to the village. Clouds covered the sky and it rained heavily on the day Guru Angad Dev Ji returned to the village.</string>
    <string name="katha9Title">Revival of Manak Chand</string>
    <string name="Katha91">Guru Amar Das Ji, the third Guru of Sikhs purchased some land in Goindwal and laid the foundation of a Bawli (a well with descending steps) in 1559. All Sikhs joined in the work of digging the Bawli. There was great activity throughout the construction of the Bawli. After digging very deep, they found large stones which hindered the progress. The underwater reserve was just below the stones. The Guru asked the Sikhs if there was any one who would be courageous to drive a peg into the base to remove the obstruction. He, however, warned that the operation had great danger because if the person could not avert the gush of water, he might drown. All Sikhs remained silent and no one came forward to take such a risk. At last, Manak Chand of Vairowal, who was married to a niece of Guru Ji, offered his services.</string>
    <string name="Katha92">Manak Chand, invoking God\'s name and through the grace of the Guru, was able to wedge through the stone and the stream of water immediately overflowed the Bawli. He was overtaken by the gush of water and drowned. However, by the grace of the Guru, his body came to the top of the water from where he was taken out by Sikhs. He was then brought back to life by Guru Amar Das Ji with the grace of God. Therefore, he was called \'Marjiwra\' (revived after death).</string>
    <string name="Katha93">The Bawli when finished yielded fresh drinkable water. The Sikhs rejoiced at the successful completion of their labor.</string>
    <string name="katha10Title">God saved Sain Ji\'s Job</string>
    <string name="Katha101">Sain was a poor man who would serve the king in his palace. "Hearing about the glory of Kabeer, Sain also became a disciple. During night, he would immerse in loving devotion of God and in the morning, he would serve the king. One night, God's devotees came to Sain's house and the whole night was spent in singing the Lord's praises. Sain could not leave the company of the holy and consequently did not perform the king?s service next morning.</string>
    <string name="Katha102">God himself took the form of Sain and served the king in such a way that the king was overjoyed. Bidding farewell to the devotees, Sain embarrassedly arrived at the palace of the king. The king called Sain from a distance. He took off his own robes and offered it to Sain. \'You have overpowered me today\', said the king and his words were heard by all. God Himself manifests the dignity of His devotees"</string>
    <string name="katha11Title">Kabeer Ji Tied Up in Chains, Saved by God</string>
    <string name="Katha111">In fourteenth century, India was ruled by muslim kings who would kill if anyone refuses to accept Islamic faith. Kabeer Ji was a true devotee of God and would eternally recite His name and mediate on God. Kabeer Ji would only worship God and none else. Kabeer Ji considered himself neither a Muslim, nor a Hindu.</string>
    <string name="Katha112">Kabeer Ji says, "I do not make pilgrimages to Mecca, nor do I worship at Hindu sacred shrines. I serve the One Lord, and not any other. I do not perform Hindu worship, nor do I practice the Muslim prayers. I have taken the One Formless Lord into my heart; I humbly worship Him there" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 1136).</string>
    <string name="Katha113">Kabeer Ji was a taylor by profession. "Abandoning weaving, Kabeer meditated on God with love. From a weaver belonging to a low caste family, he became an ocean of excellence" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 487). The king came to know about Kabeer Ji and asked him to accept Islam but Kabeer Ji refused. King ordered his soldiers to tie Kabeer Ji in chains and drown him in river Ganges. The king’s soldiers brought Kabeer near the bank of the river Ganges. There was no one with Kabeer Ji, no friend, no family but God.</string>
    <string name="Katha114">Kabeer Ji says, “The river Ganges is deep and profound. Kabeer, tied up in chains, was standing there. My mind will not shake; why should my body be afraid? My mind remained immersed with God” (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 1162). The king’s soldiers threw Kabeer Ji’s body tied up with chains in the river Ganges. Kabeer Ji describes this situation as follow, “The waves of Ganges broke my chains and Kabeer was seated on a deer skin. Kabeer says, I have no friend or companion. The Lord is my Savior on both water and land” (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 1162). God raised Kabeer Ji from water to protect His devotee. The chain broke as Kabeer’s body touched the water of Ganges river. Kabeer Ji was raised from the water sitting on the deer skin floating on the surface of the river. The king was amazed by looking at Kabeer Ji rising from water. The king was embarrassed and begged Kabeer Ji for an apology.</string>
    <string name="katha12Title">Naamdev Ji and the Hindu Priests</string>
    <string name="Katha121">Naamdev was a true devotee of God. For all of his life, Naamdev had worshipped God and had faith in Him for each and every moment. He did not worship anyone else but the one immortal God. He says, "The performance of countless millions of other devotions is not even equal to one devotion to the Name of God" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 1163). The materialistic things would not deter Naamdev’s spiritual path to meet God. He considered iron and gold alike. Once while sewing he wrote, "I perform devotional worship and sing glorious praises of God. Twenty-four hours a day, I meditate on God. I have found a needle of gold (Naam / God's Name), and a silver thread (pure mind). (Through Naam), Naamdev?s mind has been woven with God" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 485). Naamdev cared neither for gold nor for silver, he was in love with God. A result of his true worship he had became a highly spiritual person but he was still completely devoid of pride. Naamdev knew that God does care for the person who recites His name and remember Him all the time.</string>
    <string name="Katha122">Once, Naamdev Ji went to Avandanagnath Temple situated in Maharashtra, India. The Hindu priests of that temple believed in the caste system. After reaching the temple, Naamdev sat and started meditating on God but the Hindu priests grabbed his arm and drove him out of the temple. The priests said that Naamdev couldn’t visit the temple because he belonged to a low class. Naamdev was deeply hurt. He went to the back of the temple and started worshipping God. In his prayer he said, "Joyfully, I came to Your Temple, O Lord. While Naamdev was worshipping, he was driven out. I am of a low social class, O Lord; Why was I born into a family of fabric dyers? I picked up my blanket and started walking. I sat at the back side of the temple" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 1164).</string>
    <string name="Katha123">Naamdev further prayed, "Please do not forget me; do not forget me, please do not forget me, O Lord. The temple priests consider themselves of high caste, and everyone is furious with me. Calling me low-caste and untouchable, they beat me and drove me out; what should I do now, O Beloved Father Lord? If You give me salvation after I die, no one will know that I attained salvation. These Pandits, these religious scholars, call me low-born; when they say this, they tarnish Your honor as well. You are called kind and compassionate; the power of Your Arm is absolutely unrivalled" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 1292). "As Naamdev uttered the glorious praises of the Lord, the temple turned around to face the Lord's humble devotee" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 1164). "The Lord turned the temple around to face Naamdev and its back to the priests" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 1292). That temple is still rotated. This is the symbol of the true love of God towards His true devotee.</string>
    <string name="katha13Title">Leper and the Wonder Lake</string>
    <string name="Katha131">In sixteenth century, a revenue collector of Patti in district of Lahore had five daughters, the fifth daughter was very religious. One day the father asked, “who gives you to eat and drink”. The first four daughters said that it were their parents who had provided them with food and other necessities of life, but the fifth daughter told her parents that God was the only Cherisher of His creation. On hearing this reply her father got very angry and remarked, “I shall see if God will protect you.”</string>
    <string name="Katha132">One day a crippled leper came to the town and the father forcefully married his fifth daughter to him to teach her a lesson. She willfully accepted as it was her destiny. She put him in a basket and carried him on her head, and begged from door to door to maintain their livelihood. One day she left him under a tree near a lake and went to the nearby colony to beg for food.</string>
    <string name="Katha133">The leper saw some gray pigeons dipping in the water and turning white when came out of the water. The leper thought that the water had some miraculous healing power. So he left his basket and crawled into the water. Leprosy at once disappeared from his body except one finger which he left out of water while bathing. When the lady came back, she asked him the where abouts of her husband. The man said that he is her husband. She did not believe it. The man then dipped the finger that was left out of the water, which was still affected by leprosy. As soon as he dipped the finger, leprosy disappeared from that finger. His wife couldn\’t believe her eyes and ultimately went to Guru Ram Das Ji (the fourth Guru of Sikhs), who confirmed by saying that the lake possesses such extraordinary efficacy which the man illustrated. The couple became Guru\'s followers. Guru then began the construction of the Golden Temple on that lake, which was completed by Guru Arjan Dev Ji, the fifth Guru of Sikhs.</string>
    <string name="katha14Title">The King and the Queen</string>
    <string name="Katha141">Once there was a king named HariChand in India. "King HariChand had a queen with beautiful eyes, Tara. She had made his home the abode of comforts"  (The Vaars of Bhai Gurdas Ji, 10). She was a devotee of God and she knew the purpose of life. As it written in Guru Granth Sahib, "This human body has been given to you. This is your chance to meet God. All other works are of no use. Join the holy congregation and meditate on the Name of God" (Guru Granth Sahib Ji, 12).</string>
    <string name="Katha142">Every night the queen would leave the king’s palace to join the holy congregation and meditate on God. “She would join the holy congregation and spend the whole night by hearing the holy hymns. After she left, the King awoke in the middle of the night and realized she had gone. He could not find the Queen anywhere and his heart was filled with astonishment” (The Vaars of Bhai Gurdas Ji, 10).</string>
    <string name="Katha143">The King thought that Tara might be cheating on him, not realizing that Tara goes to worship and meditates on God. The queen was a great devotee of God. She would reach the holy congregation, take her sandals off, join the other devotees in worshipping and meditating on God. “The following night he followed the young queen. The queen reached the holy congregation and the King lifted one of her sandals to prove her infidelity” (The Vaars of Bhai Gurdas Ji, 10).</string>
    <string name="Katha144">The king waited outside the place where the congregation was being held. Queen came outside after meditating on God. “Because she had meditated on God in the holy congregation, one sandal became a pair. The king was astonished and realized that her matching sandal was a miracle. King said, I would devote myself to the holy congregation” (The Vaars of Bhai Gurdas Ji, 10). The matching sandal was a result of the miracle performed by God to protect His devotee.</string>
    <string name="katha15Title">Evil Greed</string>
    <string name="Katha151">Once there were four good friends. They were friends from childhood and their friendship was very deep. One day they were going on a journey through a forest. As they were walking, they felt as if something was buried under the ground. They decided to explore it and started digging. After digging, they found a big box, which was full of gold coins.</string>
    <string name="Katha152">They decided to make four parts of the gold coins and distribute it equally among themselves but deep in their hearts each one of them wanted to have the whole box of gold coins. They took the box of gold coins with them but with each step they would take, their desire of having the whole box of gold coins increased. </string>
    <string name="Katha153">The sun was about to set and the four of them decided to take shelter under a tree and have some food followed by sleep and continue their journey the next morning. They sat under the tree and decided that two of them will go in search of food and other two will guard the box. As the first two went in search of the food, they began to talk about that box of gold coins. The first one said that he wants to have as much gold as possible. The second one wanted the same. So after gather some food, an evil thought came in their mind. They added poison to the food so that their other two friends will die and they would share the box and divide the gold half and half. </string>
    <string name="Katha154">On the other end, the other two friends that were guarding the box started to talk about gold. They want the same thing, to have as much as possible. To do so, they made an evil plan too. They sharpened their knives so that when their first two friends will arrive, they would kill them.</string>
    <string name="Katha155">The moment came, their first two friends came with the food, and they placed the food on the box and sat down. As they took their seat, the other two friends with knives beheaded them in a fraction of a second. Their bodies lay dead on the ground. The other two friends were happy that they now would get the half of the gold coins each. Some time passed and they decided to have some food. Few minutes after they ate the poisoned food, their lifeless bodies lay dead on the ground and neither one of them got the gold coins. Moreover, it cost them the loss of their lives.</string>
    <string name="katha16Title">Hypocrite Priest</string>
    <string name="Katha161">Once there was a devotee of God who had a longing to meet God. He did not know Punjabi and could not understand Guru Granth Sahib Ji. He heard of a priest who translates Guru Granth Sahib Ji and narrates the message of the Guru Sahib in English. He went to the priest and joined his congregation. The priest started describing the greatness and the teachings of Guru Nanak Dev Ji. He conveyed the message of Guru Ji. As Guru instructed he said, God can only be seen by meditating on Him and remembering Him for every moment. Just as you would remember someone you love and he/she is in your mind all the time, remember God and you shall meet Him. The priest was doing holy work but he was only doing it for money. As people would leave, they would present him with some money for his time and that is what priest wanted. The priest himself would not worship God and was concentrating on making as much money as he could.</string>
    <string name="Katha162">The devotee of God became a regular follower of the priest. He would come to the priest’s congregation everyday, learn about Guru’s message and while leaving, he would leave some money for the priest. However, in order to travel to the priest’s congregation, the devotee had to cross a river. There was no bridge nearby, so he had to walk 1 mile south to get to the bridge and come back north for about 1 mile. This would take him a lot of time. The devotee decided to ask for a solution from the priest. When he asked, the priest first asked for his fee. The devote paid him and the priest told him that if he worships God from deep within his heart and has trust in Him, God will make him able to walk on water and he will no longer has to walk 2 miles to cross the bridge.</string>
    <string name="Katha163">The devotee was impressed. He had a great trust in God and started worshipping him even more than he used to. He would wake up at 3AM in the morning, take a bath and mediate on God. He would also meditate on him while running errands and working. He recited the Name of God for each moment he could.</string>
    <string name="Katha164">A month passed and the devotee was walking along the bank of the river and he was getting late. He thought if be walked a mile to the bridge and then a mile back, he would miss the most of the day’s sermon. So he decided to go through the river. As he stepped in the water, he did not become wet and neither did his foot sink in the water. He was actually walking on water. He was filled with joy and thanked God. He crossed the river by walking on the water and reached the congregation of the priest.</string>
    <string name="Katha165">After that day, he never crossed the bridge; he would walk on the water to go to the priest\'s congregation. One day, the devotee invited the priest to his house for a meal to thank him for his guidance. The priest accepted his invitation and headed along with him to his house. As they approached the river, the priest wanted to cross the river from the bridge. The devotee replied that he doesn\’t cross the bridge anymore and goes through the river. The priest asked that why does he go through the river, doesn\’t he get wet? The devotee replied that he never gets wet, he walks on water. The priest was astonished. The priest asked the devotee to cross the river first.</string>
    <string name="Katha166">The devotee crossed the river by walking on water. The priest had never seen anything like this before. He was wonderstruck and filled with astonishment. When the devotee reached the other side, he asked the priest to cross the river. Having not meditated on God, priest hesitated but to preserve his honor he thought to give it a try. As he stepped in the water, he drowned. The devotee had to pull the priest out of the river.</string>
    <string name="Katha167">Moral: Hypocrites talk about God and the teaching of Guru Ji but they seldom follow the teachings themselves. God is always with the true follower of Guru Ji, even if the follower obtains his knowledge about God from a hypocrite.</string>
    <string name="katha17Title">Why do Good People Suffer?</string>
    <string name="Katha171">Once there were two friends, one was a Gurmukh and the other was a Manmukh. Their friendship was deep but Gurmukh believed in God while Manmukh did not. Gurmukh would wake up early in the morning, take a bath and recite the holy hymns while Manmukh would still be in bed sound asleep.</string>
    <string name="Katha172">Once they were traveling through a forest. As they were passing through the forest, Manmukh found a bag of coal. He was very happy because he could sell it and make some money. As they further walked while talking about how lucky Manmukh was to find the bag of coal, Gurmukh screamed with pain. It appeared that a splinter went in Gurmukh’s foot. While Gurmukh was in pain, Manmukh started laughing. Gurmukh was surprise and asked him why was he laughing? Manmukh said, “You have been worshipping God everyday and what you got as a result is a splinter in your foot. I have never worshipped God and I still got a bag full of coal.”</string>
    <string name="Katha173">An old wise man happened to be passing by when he heard Manmukh’s comments. The old man had a big ironic smile on his face. Manmukh was astonished when he saw the old man smile. Manmukh asked the old man about the reason for his smile. The old man replied, “You are naïve. You do not worship God. You were destined to find a bag of diamonds today if you have been worshipping God. And Gurmukh, you were destined to die at the moment you got the splinter in your foot. Because you have been worshipping God, the pain of death simply turned into a splinter.”</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fragment">FragmentA</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fragment_b">FragmentB</string>
    <string name="title_activity_fragment_c">FragmentC</string>
    <string name="title_activity_splash">Sikh Gyan</string>
    <string name="title_activity_index_page">Sikh Gyan</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube_list">Sikh Gyan</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube1">Life Story of Guru Nanak dev Ji</string>
    <string name="dot">.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube2">Life Story of Guru Gobind Singh Ji</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube3">Life Story of Shri Guru Amardas Ji</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube4">Life Story of Guru Angad Dev Ji</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube5">Sri Guru Ram Das Ji</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube6">Mool Mantar</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube7">Benti Chaupai Sahib</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube8">Sikhism spirituality</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube9">Don\'t Freak, I\'m Sikh</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube10">Mullah Khatri</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube11">The Sikh Next Door</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube12">Anmol Bachan</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube13">Sikh Women in Panth</string>
    <string name="title_activity_youtube14">Saare Japo Waheguru!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_contact_me">ContactMe</string>
    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
    <string name="title_activity_stories_list">StoriesList</string>

</resources>